Hi
ANDY GRANOWITZ: Hi.
我是Andy granowitz  Google Analytics的开发技术推广工程师
Andy Granowitz here, developer advocate for Google Analytics.
今天我要谈谈  如何去配置Google Analytics
Today I'm going to talk a little about setting up Google
在初次使用的时候
Analytics for the first time.
Google Analytics因其易于在网站及移动App上
Google Analytics is known for being straightforward to deploy
部署而闻名
on your website or app.
事实的确如此
And although this is true, there are a few important things
然而在首次安装Google Analytics之前
to consider when you install Google
仍有一些重要的事情需要考虑
Analytics for the first time to make
以确保最大限度的发挥
sure you get the most out of the powerful features
Google Analytics的无穷潜力
that Google Analytics offers.
最基本的数据收集方式
The most basic measurement track--
就是在移动应用和网站上
measurement is going to be pageview or screen view
分别运用Pageview和Screen view tracking
tracking on web and app, respectively.
对于大多数网站来说  设置pageview tracking非常简单
For most websites, setting up pageview tracking is straightforward.
只需向每一个网页里
Add the Google Analytics JavaScript snippet
插入一段JavaScript跟踪代码
on every page, and Google Analytics
Google Analytics就会自动统计页面的浏览量
will count each time the page is loaded.
这点在移动应用上实现起来会有点儿复杂
This is a little bit more involved on mobile apps.
但是可以通过使用iOS或者是Android的相关SDK
But once you set up screen view tracking
设置screen view tracking  这也能达到效果
using iOS or Android SDK, the results are very similar.
Google Analytics会默认进行大量的数据收集
Google Analytics will measure a lot by default, even
即使进行了基本的设置
with this basic setup.
例如  通过设置基本的page或者是screen view tracking
For example, with just page or screen view tracking,
Google Analytics会自动地
Google Analytics will automatically
帮你分析会话时长  特定网页或者是页面的浏览时间
allow you to analyze the session duration, time
地理位置信息  比如国家地区以及城市
on specific pages or screens; geo-information, like city
以及相关技术数据  比如浏览器和移动设备信息
and state; technology data, like mobile device or browser;
每页上的用户流量
user flow between pages or screens;
以及用户的来源  比如说搜索引擎
and where users are coming from, like search engines,
社交网络 抑或是其他站点  等等
social networks, referrals from other sites, and so on.
Google Analytics会自动捕捉大量的信息
So there's a lot that's captured automatically.
但是通过个性化的定制
But with some customization, Google Analytics
Google Analytics会有的放矢选择捕捉一些
can capture user interactions that
在站点或者是移动应用上产生的
are unique to your site or app and that are really
对你来说至关重要的用户互动信息
important to your business.
Google Analytics为不同的应用场合
Google Analytics offers many different customizations
提供了多种个性化方案
for many different use cases ranging
从电子商务到资源的载入时间的统计
from measuring e-commerce to how long resources take to load,
但是在初次开始配置Google Analytics时
but there are three that I'd like
我想着重强调三个个性化方案
to highlight when first getting set up--
事件  自定义维度 以及  广告标记
events, custom dimensions, and campaign tagging.
事件是用来查看用户如何与您的网站或应用进行互动的
Events are used to measure interactions within a given
换句话说  一切不是载入网页
page, in other words, anything that is not
或者是载入应用新界面的动作
a page load or a new screen.
但是你不必统计所有的事件
But keep in mind that you don't need to measure everything.
你只需思考对你来说重要的用户互动事件
Think about what are the most important user interactions
然后有计划的统计它们
and plan to measure those.
这能有效防止在进行分析时的数据过载
This will prevent data overload when doing analysis.
自定义维度
Custom dimensions.
正如我们之前所讲  Google Analytics默认会捕捉大量的信息
As we discussed, Google Analytics captures a lot of data by default.
但是一般来讲  重要信息对你
But often, the most important information
往往会非常特别的作用
is very specific to your business,
没有了你的帮助  Google Analytics在统计关键信息时
making it difficult for Google Analytics
就变的异常困难
to measure without a little help from you.
通过自定义维度  你可以向Google Analytics导入自定义的数据
With custom dimensions, you can send custom data
然后它会自动地
to Google Analytics, which will automatically
和Google Analytics已收集的现有
get correlated with all of the other data
其他所有数据相关联起来
that Google Analytics collects.
举个例子  当用户订阅了你的实时通讯
For example, when signing up for your newsletter,
用户可以有选择的去订阅服务商
if the user has the option to identify their industry,
通过自定义维度你可以把这个信息传递给用户
you may want to pass this information as a custom dimension.
另一个例子  则是发生在用户注册你的服务时
Another example might be when a user signs up for your service,
他(她)们的可以30天免费试用
whether they signed up for the 30-day trial,
还是标准会员  亦或是高级会员
a standard membership, or a premium membership.
最后一个我想谈谈的个性化方案
The final customization that I'd like to talk about
叫做广告标记
is campaign tagging.
Google Analytics会密切的监视HTTP referer
Google Analytics looks at the HTTP refer
并且不遗余力的计算出你的流量都是从哪里来的
and does its best to figure out where your traffic is coming from.
但是当你开始使用自定义广告
But when you run custom campaigns, like through an ad
无论是通过广告网络  还是电子邮件交易
network, or if you're doing some email marketing,
亦或是其它之类的媒介
or, really, any other medium, you
你都可以使用Google Analystics的网址构建工具
can use the Google Analytics URL Builder
向推广给客户的网址中添加自定义广告系列参数
to add query parameters to the URL you're promoting to your users.
当用户点击链接  网址中所添加的参数
When users click on that link, the parameters you've added
会被Google Analytics自动识别
are automatically recognized by Google Analytics.
所以在报告中  你可以准确地知道
So in your reports, you'll be able to find out exactly
哪个广告为你的网站或者是应用带来了用户
which campaigns brought users to your site or app
以及最终他(她)们都干了什么
and what they ultimately did.
这儿有一个特例
One special case.
如果你使用Adwords服务的话  我强烈建议
If you use AdWords, I strongly recommend
将Google Analytics和AdWords账户关联起来
that you link Google Analytics and AdWords accounts.
这样做  AdWords会自动地
By doing so, your AdWords campaigns will automatically
将广告参数标记出来
get tagged with campaign parameters,
大量的数据会被导入到Google Analytics账户
and a lot of other valuable data will
促进数据间的互惠共享
be imported into your Google Analytics account.
除了能和AdWords紧密关联
In addition to this deep integration with AdWords,
Google Analytics也可以和Google的其他产品
Google Analytics can also integrate
密切结合  比如AdSence  Webmaster Tools
with other Google products, such as AdSense, Webmaster Tools,
AdMod  以及其他
AdMob, and more.
你要确保找到对你来说最容易的方式
Be sure to find out if there's an easy way
来连接Google Analytics
to connect Google Analytics and whatever
无论你用的什么技术  也不论他们是不是Google家的
technologies you are using, whether they are Google or not.
想要获取更多的相关个性化信息
For more information on these customizations and more,
请登陆屏幕下方的网址  developers.google.com/analytics
check out the links below or go to developers.google.com/analytics.